Mostafa Ashraf Ahmed

Tender & Procurement Engineer

You can check my portfolio on the following website: https://shorturl.at/ajstE

Contact Details



Mostafaashraf518@gmail.com



0112-610-3399



Block 2, Gazair Street, Maadi, El-Gadeda, Cairo.

Extracurricular skills

- Capable of communicating with people from different levels.
- Capable of physical heavy manual outdoor work.
- Mobility and ability to work under pressure.
- No restriction for working abroad at any place any time.

Languages

- Arabic Native
- English Intermediate
- Germany Level A2
- French Level A1

Personal information

- Date Birth: 14 Jan. 1997.
- Nationality: Egyptian.
- Marital status: Married.



Being a civil engineer, I truly understand my duty as a civil engineer. What I enjoy the most in my work is to combine the design information and realistic action. It makes me more profession and intelligent. With over 4 years of experience, I am confident that I can manage my site and facing problems with the most effective and professional approach, regardless of their age or level. Seeking a challenging position as a key person in distinctive company working in Fields utilizing my skills and knowledge to the maximum.



Professional Experience

03/2024 - till now {Senior Procurement Engineer at Orascom

Construction }

- Set the procurement plan.
- Breakdown of item.
- Send RFQ to get offers from suppliers or subcontractors.
- Compare between the vendor's offers or the subcontractor's offers.
- Start the negotiation process with vendors to minimize the cost and coordinate payment terms.
- Review the contract requests -sent by the site- and negotiate the contract conditions with the supplier/subcontractor to reach a win-win situation.
- Data Analysis.
- Ensure that tenders meet company commercial guidelines and have the necessary sign off in accordance with the delegation of authority guidelines.

-09/202103/2024 Tender and Procurement Engineer at JV Redcon

Concrete Plus{

- 1. Mohamed Naguib Electrical Express Train Station " Project Estimated Value: 600 M EGP"
- Marsa Matroh Electrical Express Train Station "Project Estimated Value: 800 M EGP" 2.
- Cathedral Light Rail Transit station "Project Estimated Value: 400 M EGP"
- Al Alamin Electrical Express Train Bridges" Project Estimated Value: HRT Br-5 (250M EGP)"
- Al Alamin Electrical Express Train Bridges "Project Estimated Value: HRT Br-6 (350M EGP)"
- 6. Al Alamin Electrical Express Train Bridges" Project Estimated Value: HRT Br-7 (180M EGP)"
 - Prepare technical & commercial proposals.
 - Attend clarification meetings with Client when required.
 - Set the procurement plan.
 - Breakdown of item.
 - Send RFQ to get offers from suppliers or subcontractors.
 - Compare between the vendor's offers or the subcontractor's offers.
 - Start the negotiation process with vendors to minimize the cost and coordinate payment
 - Review the contract requests -sent by the site- and negotiate the contract conditions with the supplier/subcontractor to reach a win-win situation.
 - Data Analysis.
 - Ensure that tenders meet company commercial guidelines and have the necessary sign off in accordance with the delegation of authority guidelines.

09/2019-06/2021 (CONCRETE PLUS)

• 04/2021-06/2021 { Technical office QS} (Hospital Project "El-Arish Hospital")

- Perform takeoff of various items from the approved shop drawings and issue the revised
- Monitor project monthly progress.
- Prepare and review monthly payment for contractor.
- Review monthly timesheets for work and compare with budget.
- preparing invoices check sub-contractor invoices.
- Comparing the BOQ with the site, and making a reports.

❖ 09/2019-04/2021 {Site engineer at Concrete plus} (Hospital Project "Kafr El-Sheikh Hospital")

- · Interpretation of Drawing
- Allotting Work to Labors
- **Supervision of Construction Work**
- Preparing a Schedule of Material Used and Available-Checking Steel Work of Slab, Beam, & Column Before Concreting

06/2019-09/2019 { Training as a Planning Engineer at HSE}

- ensuring plans meet the client's specifications.
- making estimations for timescales and costs.
- supervising the project at all stages and providing solutions to problems, collaborating with site managers, surveyors, engineers, site worker and other professionals, organizing the transportation of materials, ensuring procedures are carried out safely.
- assisting Planning Engineer in preparing, managing and maintaining schedules, progress and reports.
- assisting in preparing baseline program, milestones, deliverables and timelines as per project management plan, and preparing daily, weekly and monthly reports.

2018-2019 {Training as Planning Engineer TABARAK group.(90 avenue)}

- Assist Planning Engineer in preparing, managing and maintaining schedules, progress and reports.
- Assist in preparing baseline program, schedules, milestones, deliverables and timelines as per project management plan. Prepare daily, weekly and monthly reports.

2017-2018 (Training as a Site Engineer at ACC. (Extension of 57357 Hospital))

{concrete works like: Columns-Beams-Slabs (Hollow, Flat, Solid)-Tanks }

{Training as a Site Engineer at TABARAK group.(CAPITAL EAST)}

{finishing works like: painting-plumbing works-Electricity works-flooring works }

{Training as a Site Engineer at DORRA GROUP. (The villas)} 2015-2016

{finishing works like: painting-plumbing works-Electricity works-flooring works }



EDUCATION

2014-2019 Bachelor of Civil Engineering, 2019.

- Faculty of Engineering, Civil Engineering and Structural Engineering, with cumulative Grade is Very Good.
- •Concrete project: Reinforced concrete Structures, with Excellent Grade.
- 2017 Course of training program SAP 2000.
- 2018 Course of training program Revit Structure Essentials.
- 2018 Course of training program Primavera & Project Management.
- 2022 Course of training program Data Analysis from Google. (I completed 5 courses out of 8)
- 2022 Course of training program Data Analysis from IBM. (I completed 2 courses out of 9)
- 2023 Course of training program full stack Web Developer from Instant (I completed front-end)



Design of any structural system and get the concrete dimension and RFT.

Proficient in the following:

- AutoCAD.
- SAP 2000.
- ETABS 2019.
- SAFE 16.
- Revit.

- Primavera P6.
- Microsoft Office.
- Nevus.
- MS Project.
- Cost Estimation.
- Forecast.

- Data Visualization.
- Data Analysis.
- SQL.
- Python.
- HTML.
- CSS.
- JavaScript.